Shobha Patel

shobhapatel310@gmail.com | +91 7987939057|

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shobha-patel/ | GitHub: https://github.com/spgenius/

EDUCATION

GURU GHASIDAS VISH-WAVIDYALAYA (CENT-RAL UNIVERSITY)

BTECH | COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING Bilaspur, Chattisgarh 2014 - 2018 Cum. GPA: 8.9 / 10

BRIGHT CAREER HIGH-ER SECONDARY SCHOOL

MP BOARD

2012 | Pipariya, India Percentage - 91.00%

GOVT. GIRLS HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL MP BOARD

2010 | Pipariya, India Percentage -84.33 %

OPERATING SYSTEM

Linux (Ubuntu) | Windows

SKILLS

Python | PySpark | AWS | Foundary | Flask | SQL | Hadoop | Jupyter | Java | JavaScript | Git | Jenkins | Jira | Postman

FAMILIAR WITH:

C++ | C | ML | Deep Learning | NLP

Trainings & Certifications:

Machine Learning | Python | Kaggle | 2021 ML | Deep Learning | Python | Udemy | 2021

SUMMARY:

A total of 4.10 years of Industry Experience as a Software Engineer with 3 years of Hands-on Experience in **Python**, **PySpark**, **SQL**, **RedShift and AWS**. Extensive knowledge in **Python** with Libraries such as **Numpy**, **Pandas etc.** Worked on tools like **PyCharm**, **DBeaver Jupyter Notebook**, **Visual Studio**, **Flask** etc.

EXPERIENCE:

IMPETUS TECHNOLOGIES, BENGALURU – Sr. SOFTWARE ENGINEER | MAR 2022 – CURRENT

Working as **Big Data Engineer** with UAL.

Developed and delivered high-quality 40 pipelines to flow the data from esftp to redshift, EDW & Foundry for United Currency Bank using Airflow, AWS, Python using flask & PySpark Glue Job, Postgres SQL etc, working in a team as a team player, and support organizations, with on-time go live, quick defect patching, unit testing, code review and documentation. During working on the pipelines, we created preprocessor using PySpark & Python to convert source files into parquet format and postprocessor using PySpark to apply SCD Logic 2 in the pipelines, created syncs from Redshift to Foundry.

METRICSTREAM, BENGALURU - MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF | SEPT 2018 - FEB 2022

- > Key achievement:
- Received the STAR Award for FY2021 for excellent work single-handedly completed the ICW upgrade in the Local environment, UAT and Production. Also, parallelly completed NBS account upgrade with team.
- Received SPOT Award for FY'21 Q2 for outstanding work as a Developer for 2 projects - ICW and NBS.
- Developed and delivered high-quality GRC product (M7) features for 4 customers projects, working in a team with product management, QA and support organizations, with on-time go live, quick defect patching, and responsive Production support.
- Designed database schemas and their relationships keeping normalization under consideration..
- **Performed git operations** like Checkout, Pull, Commit, Push and Merge to maintain a complete history of the code on Git.
- Implemented chargeable change requests (CRs) to the product using JavaScript (JS), Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, Java, AWS, Python and increased revenue by 25% from the customer.

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

MOVIE RECOMMENDATION | ANACONDA | PYTHON | FLASK | HEROKU

 This is a Flask web application which provides all the details of the requested movie such as overview, genre, release date, rating, runtime, top cast, reviews, recommended movies, etc. Performed feature engineering & preprocessing using numpy, pandas, nltk libraries.

App Link: https://movies-recommender-app-mrs.herokuapp.com/
Git Repo Link for Movie Recommender System

Hadoop with Big Data | IIHT Ltd | 2017 Java Training (6 Weeks) | Ducat | 2016

INTERESTS

Competitive Programming • 3D Modeling & Sculpting • Drawing • Badminton • Gaming Quora • Web-Surfing • Workout Lover

SENTIMENT PREDICTION OF TWEETS USING NAÏVE BAYES CLASSIFIER | HADOOP | JAVA

While working on this project I have collected data from Twitter by using twitter4j API (Streaming API) then pre-processing of the tweets is done to remove redundant and unnecessary information like removing URLs, username, special symbols, stopwords etc. Once our training data set is ready then calculated the word frequency with the help of MapReduce Framework (Hadoop) & used Naïve Bayes Classifier to predict sentiments (like Anger, Sad, Love, Joy & Surprise) from tweets.
 Git Repo Link for Sentiment-Analysis